Guide to the John Betjeman Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1908-1989; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Other Papers
    - Sketchbook, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 317)
      Contains pen and ink and water colour drawings (largely of buildings)
    - Drawings by Betjeman, 1946-1953, undated (Box 6, Folder 318)
      Includes pen and ink and water colour drawings of buildings, Colonel Kolkhorst, and doodles
    - Desk Diary, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 319)
    - Ephemera regarding Honorary Doctorate, University of Hull, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 320)
    - Ephemera regarding Honorary Doctorate, Oxford University, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 321)
    - Menus and matchbook from Betjeman Carving Restaurant, Charing Cross Hotel, circa 1989 (Box 6, Folder 322)
- Printed Material, 1946-1990; Series IV; 4.0 linear feet (4 boxes)
  The series is organized into three subseries: Clippings; Booklets, Brochures, and Pamphlets; and Material Collected by Duncan Andrews. The clippings are arranged in chronological order. Prior to processing some clippings were grouped into various subjects, which are retained here and arranged alphabetically by topic.
  The series contains publications about Betjeman and his family, namely clippings, pamphlets, brochures, and booklets, dating from 1946 to 1990. The majority of the printed material consists of clippings obtained by Duncan Andrews through a news clippings service, largely during the 1970s, and concerns Betjeman's work as a preservationist.
  The subseries Pamphlets, Brochures, and Booklets includes ephemera relating to events in which Betjeman participated, varying from readings to fundraisers for churches. Programs from memorial services held in Betjeman's honour following his death in 1984 are also found in the subseries.
  Other Printed Material Collected by Duncan Andrews pertains to Andrews's work in creating and promoting his John Betjeman collection (for instance, exhibition and book dealers' catalogues). Ephemera removed from Andrews's book collection – such as printed ephemera and correspondence – is also located in this subseries. Andrews's book collection contained his own books and some formerly belonging to Betjeman. The book from which individual items were removed is recorded with each item.
  - Clippings
    - General
      - 1946 February - 1974 May (Box 6, Folder 323-350)
      - 1974 June - 1977 February (Box 7, Folder 351-371)
      - 1977 March - 1990 January, undated (Box 8, Folder 372-386)
      - Receipts, circa 1950-1980 (Box 8, Folder 387-388)
    - Topical
      - "Anecdotes", 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 389)
      - "Anthologies -- Non-fiction", 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 390)
      - "Anthologies -- Poetry", 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 391)
      - "Architectural Review", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 392)
      - "Astrology and Numerology", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 393)
      - "Betjemania", 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 394-397)
      - "Biographical and Interviews", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 398)
      - "Birthday Announcements", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 399)
      - "Books -- Collected Poetry", 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 400)
      - "Books -- Non-fiction", 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 401)
      - "Brief Citations", 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 402)
      - "Ceremonies Performed", 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 403)
      - "Competitions Judged", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 404)
      - "Conservation -- All Saint's Church, Tooting", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 405)
      - "Conservation -- Baptist Tabernacle, Swindon", 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 406)
      - "Conservation -- Baulking", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 407)
      - "Conservation -- Bloomsbury Homes", 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 408)
      - "Conservation -- Bradpole Church Bells", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 409)
      - "Conservation -- Brighton West Pier", 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 410)
      - "Conservation -- Camel River Marina", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 411)
      - "Conservation -- Clevedon Pier", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 412)
      - "Conservation -- Countess of Huntingdon's Chapel", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 413)
      - "Conservation -- Crown Liquor Saloon", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 414)
      - "Conservation -- Dicken's Home", 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 415)
      - "Conservation -- Electric Palace", 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 416)
      - "Conservation -- Grand Theatre, Blackpool", 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 417)
      - "Conservation -- Green Park Station", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 418)
      - "Conservation -- Guyhirn Chapel", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 419)
      - "Conservation -- Hillrise House, Walton", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 420)
      - "Conservation -- Holy Trinity Church", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 421)
      - "Conservation -- Isle of Wight Ferry", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 422)
      - "Conservation -- Keats' House", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 423)
      - "Conservation -- Liverpool Street Station", 1975 (Box 8, Folder 424)
      - "Conservation -- National Piers Society", 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 425)
      - "Conservation -- Oundle Chapel", 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 426)
      - "Conservation -- Palace Theatre", 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 427)
      - "Conservation -- Park Crescent, Abingdon", 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 428)
      - "Conservation -- Pheasantry Club, Chelsea", 1975 (Box 8, Folder 429)
      - "Conservation -- Piers Art Centre, Stromness", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 430)
      - "Conservation -- Pont Street, Chelsea", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 431)
      - "Conservation -- Prussia Cove", 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 432)
      - "Conservation -- Rothay Hotel, Wordsworth Village, Grasmere", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 433)
      - "Conservation -- St. Andrew's, Cullompton", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 434)
      - "Conservation --St. Andrew's Church, Wraysbury", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 435)
      - "Conservation --St. Andrew's Church Clock, Soho", 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 436)
      - "Conservation -- St. Erkenwald's Church", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 437)
      - "Conservation -- St. Mary-le-Strand", 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 438)
      - "Conservation -- St. Mary's Parish Church, Battersea", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 439)
      - "Conservation -- St. Michael's and All Angels Parish Church", 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 440)
      - "Conservation -- St. Michael's Parochial Parish Church, Stourport", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 441)
      - "Conservation -- St. Pancras Station / British Library", 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 442)
      - "Conservation -- Southland Pier", 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 443)
      - "Conservation -- Spring Bank Cemetery", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 444)
      - "Conservation -- Sydney Street, Chelsea", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 445)
      - "Conservation -- Thirties Society", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 446)
      - "Conservation -- Thomas Gray Monument", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 447)
      - "Conservation -- Tantine Hotel, Stourport", 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 448)
      - "Conservation -- Turner Watercolours", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 449)
      - "Conservation -- United Reformed Church, Maswell Hill", 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 450)
      - "Conservation -- Wells Cathedral", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 451)
      - "Conservation -- Westminster Cathedral", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 452)
      - "Conservation -- Wilton's Music Hall", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 453)
      - "Conservation -- Yardley Chase Airport Opposition", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 454)
      - "Conservation -- Various Projects", 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 455-457)
      - "Coronation Street (T.V. Show)", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 458-459)
      - "Donations", 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 460)
      - "Elgar Memorial", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 461)
      - "Ephemera Society", 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 462)
      - "Family", 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 463)
      - "Honorary Degrees", 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 464)
      - "Introductions and Prefaces", 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 465)
      - "Jubilee Hymn", 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 466-468)
      - "Lowry Gallery", 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 469)
      - "Memorials", 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 470)
      - "Metroland", 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 471)
      - "Musical Adaptations and Stage Productions", 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 472-473)
      - "Office of Poet Laureate", 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 474)
      - "Opposition to Green Giant", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 475)
      - "Poems -- Christmas", 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 476)
      - "Poems -- Diary of a Church Mouse", 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 477)
      - "Poems -- Olympic Girl and Subaltern Love-Song", 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 478)
      - "Poems -- Quotes, Citations, References, and Readings", 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 479)
      - "Poems --Slough", 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 480)
      - "Portraits", 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 481)
      - "The Queen's Realm", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 482)
      - "Quotations", 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 483-487)
      - "Radio", 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 488-489)
      - "Readings", 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 490)
      - "Renaming of Montfort Restaurant", 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 491)
      - "Reviews", 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 492)
      - "Revised Book of Common Prayer", 1979 (Box 9, Folder 493)
      - "Royal Society of Literature", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 494)
      - "Societies", 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 495)
      - "Somerset House Turner Exhibit", 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 496)
      - "Spoken Recordings", 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 497)
      - "Summoned by Bells", 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 498)
      - "Television, Film Productions, Appearances", 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 499-500)
      - "Dylan Thomas in Poet's Corner", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 501)
      - "Edward Thomas Memorial", 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 502)
      - Untitled, 1970-1980 (Box 9, Folder 503-512)
  - Booklets, Brochures, and Pamphlets
    - Programs for events and publications with Betjeman, 1959-1974 (Box 9, Folder 513-514)
    - Programs memorializing Betjeman, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 515-516)
    - Brochures for various appeals to which Betjeman lent support, 1958-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 517)
    - Broadside for the opening of the Festival of the City of London, 1961
    - Material relating to friends and family, 1961-1981 (Box 9, Folder 518)
  - Other Printed Material Collected by Duncan Andrews
    - Catalogue (including paste-ups), photographs, and other ephemera relating to exhibition on John Betjeman at Wellesley College, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 519-521)
    - Book dealers' catalogues and exhibition catalogues, 1974-1989 (Box 9, Folder 522)
    - Ephemera removed from printed material, circa 1950-1980 (Box 9, Folder 523-525)
      Includes some correspondence and notes
    - Catalogue cards removed from printed material, undated (Box 9, Folder 526)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1936-1971; Series V; 3.0 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series is restricted pending digital reformatting. Consult Access Services for information about reference copies.
  The series is organized into four subseries: Radio; Television; Home Recordings; and Unidentified. Arranged chronologically.
  This series is comprised of audiovisual recordings, encompassing reel-to-reel sound recordings as well as film and VHS videotapes, which capture Betjeman's radio and television appearances. This work is of interest since it is largely through this medium that he became a household name.
  The majority of the recordings were made in the 1960s and 1970s, although some recordings are from an earlier period, the earliest dating from 1936 (this being Betjeman's broadcast for BBC's "West Country Calendar" on "May Games or Matter for a May Morning"). While the recordings largely document Betjeman's work with the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), the series includes one sound recording from his personal life, possibly of a visit of Andrews with Betjeman and Chetwode.
  In his radio work Betjeman read his own poetry and that of others as well as conducting interviews and investigations into topics such as architecture, religion, and literature. Among the television programmes in the collection are Betjeman's series for BBC such as "Four With Betjeman" in which he discusses a set of Victorian architects and "Bird's-Eye View" in which Betjeman explores England by helicopter. Betjeman's appearances on other programmes are also represented in the recordings; for example, his radio interview by teenagers on BBC's "Let's Find Out." The majority of Betjeman's television work is documented through audio recordings.
  - Radio
    - "Café Royal: A Study in Conversation and Reminiscence", "Tennyson - a beginning and an end", BBC Home Service, 1968 December 17; 1; 01:24:06; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365042)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Choirs and the Places Where They Sing: Leeds Parish Church," BBC Radio 3, 1967 October 22; 1; 01:31:46; The program is distorted at times. The program is recorded at a very low level. The beginning of the tape to about 01:03:44 is barely audible. There is a gap in the audio from about 01:04:30 to 01:30:02. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365059)
    - "Choirs and the Places Where They Sing: St. John's College, Oxford," BBC Radio 3, 1967 October 29; 1; 00:40:51; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365067)
    - "Scenes That Are the Brightest: A Sense of Place" and "Scenes That Are the Brightest: Up Stream," Parts 3 and 4, BBC Radio 4, 1969 March 16 and March 23; 1; 01:29:46; The program is distorted at times. The audio sounds weak at times. Static and a high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. High frequency background noise can be heard in the last six minutes of the tape. Volume fluctuations and several blank sections appear in the last six minutes. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365075)
    - "Betjeman's Dickens," BBC Radio 4, 1970 June 9; 1; 01:25:41; High frequency background noise can be heard on the tape. Static can also be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365083)
    - Untitled, various recordings, BBC, 1936-1964; 1; 02:06:45; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365091)
      Includes: "West Country Calendar: May Games or Matter for a May Morning" (1936 May 18); "Three in Hand. Three Churches (3): St. Marks, Swindon" (1948 August 4); "John Betjeman Reads a Selection of His Own Poetry (1949 August 20); "John Betjeman Reads His Own Poems," (1949 October 6); "Trains of Thought" (1953 May 8); "The Faith in the West" (1953 October 6); "Conversation Piece" (1956 December 23); possibly "John Betjeman Reads a Selection from His Collected Poems" (1958 December 26 or 28); "People Today" (1959 December 24); "Summoned by Bells" (1960 November); Lady Montgomery Massingberd interview (1961 June); "Portrait of Martin Willson" (1962 March 11); "Royal Academy of Arts: Annual Dinner" (1962 May 1); "Let's Find Out" (1962 August 10); possibly "New Comment" (1963 July); "Hugh Gaitskell" (1964 January 16); "John Betjeman" (1964 June 15).
    - Untitled, BBC Radio 3, 1961 October 8; 1; 00:40:50; The program is recorded at a very low level. There is a high amount of hiss on the tape. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365109)
  - Television
    - "Panorama," BBC, 1958 June 30
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Untitled, various recordings, BBC
      Betjeman interviews Eden Phillpotts
      Audiorecording
    - "John Betjeman Goes by Train," British Transport Films and BBC East Anglia, 1962
    - "Betjeman's London (6): Let's All Go Down to the Strand," Redifussion Network, 1967 September 18; 1; 00:24:16; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365117)
    - "The Picture Theatre," John Betjeman of some London cinemas, BBC-1, 1967 October 10; 1; 00:23:03; The program is recorded at a very low level. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365125)
    - "Summoned by Bells," 21 poems and extracts, "Look, Listen + Learn", BBC School Programmes, 1968; 1; 01:00:43; The program is recorded at a very high level. There is a high amount of buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365133)
    - "Contrasts: Tennyson -- A Beginning and an End," BBC-1, 1968 December 17; 1; 01:41:06; Static is heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365141)
      See also: "Café Royal: A Study in Conversation and Reminiscence", "Tennyson - a beginning and an end", BBC Home Service
    - Untitled, 1968 December 25; 1; 01:36:48; High frequency background noise can be heard on the tape. Static can also be heard. The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365158)
    - "Bird's-Eye View: The Englishman's Home," BBC-2, 1969 March; 1; 00:50:47; The program is recorded at a very low level. Static and buzz can be heard on the tape. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365166)
    - "Bird's-Eye View: Beside the Seaside," BBC-2, 1969 December 25; 1; 00:45:36 (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365174)
    - "Four with Betjeman (1-4): Victorian Architects and Architecture," BBC-2, 1970 June and July; 1; 01:56:52; Static and a high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 10, Item barcode 39002099365182)
    - "Four with Betjeman (1-2): Victorian Architects and Architecture," BBC-2, June 1968 and 1970; 1; 02:52:25; There's a high amount of hum and buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The tape was recorded at a low level at about 02:10:30 until the end of the program. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365190)
      Shows on Charles Barry, Augustus Pugin, William Butterfield, G.E. Street, and Gilbert Scott.
      Reel also includes two partially identified recordings: Betjeman at King's College, Canterbury (1970 June 26) for ITV and a portrait of Tennyson (1968 September 6) for BBC Radio 4.
    - "Four with Betjeman (3): Victorian Architects and Architecture," BBC-2, 1970 July 13; 1; 01:53:05; Static can be heard on the tape. The sound sounds a bit hollow at times. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365208)
      Show on Alfred Waterhouse and Norman Shaw. A newspaper clipping of the event is included.
    - "Look, Stranger: Ellan Vannin," Isle of Man, BBC-2, 1970 December 10; 1; 00:20:34; A high amount of hum and buzz can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard as well. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365216)
      Reel also includes partially identified recording of quotations from "Bird's-Eye View" with commentary by James Plunkett
    - "Bird's Eye View: Inis Fáil," BBC-2, 1971 March 17; 1; 00:58:21; Static and a high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365224)
      Commentary by James Plunkett
  - Home Recording
    - "Wantage Weekend", 1969 March 2; 1; 00:41:30; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted for the first 41 minutes. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365232)
      Notes state: "DA [Duncan Andrews ?], JB [John Betjeman], PB [Penelope Chetwode], and Wendy (at piano)"
  - Unidentified
    - "41 Poems", 3 and 4, undated; 1; 01:34:39; The program was recorded at a very high level. The program is distorted at times. A high amount of background noise can be heard. There is a gap in sound at 21:11-38:18. The program is barely audible from 01:14:10-01:18:20. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365240)
    - "Edgware RD (JB)" and "Cowper", undated; 1; 00:34:34; The program is distorted at times. The audio was recorded at a very low level. There is a gap in audio at 26:19-27:42 and again at 28:25-30:43. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365257)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 01:13:27; High frequency background noise can be heard from the beginning of the program to 28:53. The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hum can be heard. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365265)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:35:42; There are speed fluctuations on the tape. The beginning of the program is nearly inaudible and again from about 25:03-34:13. Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365273)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 01:17:24; A high amount of hum and static can be heard on the tape. The program was recorded at a low level from 07:49 until the end of the tape. High frequency background noise can also be heard during this time. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365281)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:40:30 (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365299)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:40:30; The program is distorted at times. Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365307)
      A note reads: "5x6 scripts already supplied. This does not include 'Cafe Royal'".
    - "John Betjeman", undated; 1; 01:05:49; The program is distorted at times. (Box 11, Item barcode 39002099365315)
    - Unidentified film reels, Before 1971
    - "Betjeman II, III", undated; GENMSS675_0002; 1; 01:45:11 (Box 11, Item barcode 39002102300382)
    - "Betjeman IV,V,VI", undated; GENMSS675_0003; 1; 02:44:43 (Box 11, Item barcode 39002102300390)
    - Unidentified, undated; GENMSS675_0004; 1; 01:03:43 (Box 11, Item barcode 39002102300408)
    - Unidentified, undated; GENMSS675_0001; 1; 03:07:19 (Box 12, Item barcode 39002102300275)
      The contents of the video appear to be mix of several different programs. At 00:57:54, a program called Time With Betjeman is recorded. It runs to 01:47:19. The copyright is dated 1983. Other programming include footage of Duran Duran performing and a tennis match between Ivan Lendl and Jimmy Connors.
- Oversize, 12.0 linear feet (10 boxes)
  - Church Poems, galley proofs, corrected, 1978 February 8 (Box BSD, folder 559)
  - Church Poems, paste-ups, 1980 (Box 13 (Oversize), Folder 560)
  - Uncollected Poems, galley proofs, 1982 (Box 13 (Oversize), Folder 561)
  - "Narcissus," galley proof for London Magazine, circa 1958 (Box 13 (Oversize), Folder 562)
  - Musical score set to Betjeman's poem by Mervyn Horder, 1975 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 563)
  - "Ballet-Goer's London Guide," drafts, holograph, 1952 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 564)
  - "Introduction." Casson, Hugh Maxwell. Sketch Book: A Personal Choice of London Buildings, Drawn 1971-1974, printed version, signed, 1975 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 565)
  - "Betjemania," programs, posters, publicity material and other correspondence, 1980 (Box Roll 1, Folder 566)
  - Stanford, Derek. John Betjeman: A Study, author's notebooks, holograph and drafts, typescript, corrected; related correspondence; and original photographs and illustrations used in the publication, circa 1961 (Box 15 (Oversize), Folder 568-570)
  - Menus and matchbook from Betjeman Carving Restaurant, Charing Cross Hotel, circa 1989 (Box 15 (Oversize), Folder 571)
  - General clippings, 1946 February - 1990 January, undated (Box 16 (Oversize), Folder 572-578)
  - General clippings, 1946 February - 1990 January, undated (Box 17 (Oversize), Folder 579-583)
  - General clippings, 1946 February - 1990 January, undated (Box 18 (Oversize), Folder 584-587)
  - General clippings, 1946 February - 1990 January, undated (Box 19 (Oversize), Folder 588-591)
  - Topical clippings, "Books -- Collected Poetry," "Brief Citations," "Family," "Introductions and Prefaces," "Jubilee Hymn," "Portraits," "Radio," and "Television, Film Productions, Appearances", 1975-1980 (Box 20 (Oversize), Folder 592-599)
  - Broadside for the opening of the Festival of the City of London, 1961 (Box 20 (Oversize), Folder 600)
  - "John Betjeman Goes by Train," British Transport Films and BBC East Anglia, 1962 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 601)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Unidentified film reels, Before 1971 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 602-604)